All right so let's continue with our dialogue and we're going to get a little bit more into the actual
好吧，让我们继续我们的对话，我们将更深入地了解实际情况
dates the nights that we're staying.
约会我们住的夜晚。
I'm going to start with the previous line that we talked about from the 18th to the 22nd.
我将从我们从 18 日到 22 日谈到的上一行开始。
So the receptionist will often try to confirm information to be very clear.
所以接待员经常会尽量把信息确认的很清楚。
So there are no misunderstandings.
所以没有误解。
So four nights just to confirm is that right.
所以四晚只是为了确认是正确的。
So anytime you want to confirm information we often say is that right.
所以任何时候你想确认我们常说的信息是对的。
You first say the detail and then you say is that right.
你先说细节，然后你说是对的。
So you want 30.
所以你要30。
Is that right.
那正确吗。
The very useful way to confirm information.
确认信息的非常有用的方法。
OK.
好的。
Checking out on the 22nd checking out on the 22nd.
22日退房，22日退房。
No sorry.
不抱歉。
Five nights checking out on the twenty third.
五晚二十三号退房。
So it's important to get clarification because sometimes the guest may be confused about as I talked
因此，澄清这一点很重要，因为有时客人可能会在我谈话时感到困惑
about the difference between days and nights.
关于白天和黑夜的区别。
It can be a little confusing.
这可能有点令人困惑。
So 18th 19th 20th 21st 22nd five nights checking out on the twenty third.
所以 18 日 19 日 20 日 21 日 22 日 五晚 23 日退房。
Not staying the night of the twenty third checking out means that's when you're going to leave that's
不留宿二十三晚退房意味着那是你要离开的时候
when you're going out.
当你出去的时候。
OK.
好的。
I got it I got it.
我明白了，我明白了。
Is it just you now they could also ask how many guests how many guests if it's a larger booking than
是你现在他们还可以问有多少客人如果这是一个更大的预订有多少客人
they might say how many rooms if you suggest something about you needing maybe multiple rooms at the
如果您建议您可能需要多个房间，他们可能会说有多少房间
beginning they'll say Oh how many rooms do you need maybe your booking for a group of people.
一开始他们会说哦，你需要多少房间，也许是你为一群人预订的。
But here you just said I need to book a room I need to book a room.
但是这里你刚刚说我需要预订房间我需要预订房间。
So we want to know how many people will be in that room.
所以我们想知道那个房间里会有多少人。
How many guests.
多少客人。
Is it just you.
难道只有你。
OK.
好的。
Me and my wife.
我和我的妻子。
I could say to two guests and I could if I wanted to say this one just me and my wife only two I could
我可以对两位客人说，如果我想说这个只有我和我的妻子只有两个我可以
also say only two guests justice just two guests.
还说只有两个客人正义只是两个客人。
All of those are OK ways to say this.
所有这些都可以这么说。
Now sometimes the guest you the person who's going to stay there will want to know if there are rooms
现在有时客人，你将要留在那里的人会想知道是否有房间
available on those dates.
在这些日期可用。
You might ask for example.
例如，您可能会问。
Do you have.
你有。
Do you have any vacancies.
你们有空缺吗。
Instead of saying just the dates maybe it's a very busy weekend coming up.
与其说只是日期，不如说是一个非常忙碌的周末即将到来。
You know there are many many people coming to the city for maybe a conference or something like that.
你知道有很多人来这个城市参加会议或类似的活动。
And you're worried that maybe the hotel will have no space so you could say do you have any vacancies
你担心酒店可能没有空间所以你可以说你有空位吗
for the weekend of the twenty eighth for example for the weekend of the 28.
28 日的周末，例如 28 日的周末。
Do you have any vacancies.
你们有空缺吗。
Unfortunately sir we don't have any vacancies.
不幸的是，先生，我们没有任何空缺。
We don't have any vacancies.
我们没有任何空缺。
We are fully booked.
我们已经订满了。
So if a restaurant or a hotel has no more space no more vacancy.
因此，如果餐厅或酒店没有更多空间，则没有更多空缺。
And sometimes there will be a sign outside of a small hotel which says no vacancy no space available.
有时在一家小旅馆外面会有一个牌子，上面写着没有空位，没有可用空间。
They're fully booked.
他们已经订满了。
OK so maybe you're calling around to different hotels.
好的，所以也许你正在打电话到不同的酒店。
Finally you've found the Volt maybe not a very popular hotel and they have some vacancies so you could
最后，您发现 Volt 可能不是一家非常受欢迎的酒店，而且他们有一些空缺，所以您可以
ask like that normally you don't need to do that normally you just say I'd like to book several nights.
像这样问通常你不需要这样做你只是说我想预订几个晚上。
I'd like to book three nights from the twenty third.
我想从二十三号起订三个晚上。
OK so that's only when you think that maybe they won't have spaces available.
好的，只有当您认为他们可能没有可用空间时.